NETFLIX PRESENTS
I can't hear anything!
Can you enlarge the letters
on the prompter, please?
Eleven seconds behind.
This is our last call-in contest
of this millennium.
Let's take a look at the awards.
Turn it into a ritual.
Smile and change your pose.
We'll greet the year 2000 together!
The igloo is three meters tall.
It took the kids two days to build.
This is how you spend
your free time, right?
We'd like to do something spectacular.
-Wait!
-Hello, Ms. Mira! Come on in!
I'm here!
Laura, choose the shoes for me!
What's this? Who gave it to her?
This is my New Year's dress.
Honey, take it off.
No time for the wardrobe. Laura!
I'm so sorry.
You know how long it took?
-Mira, but…
-I'm sorry.
I had a rehearsal for New Year's Eve.
You're on duty
and you're paid, aren't you?
A TV contest. Don't exaggerate.
What's this?
A show of strength? A punishment?
-A replacement.
-For whom?
Honey, take it off. We have no time.
-We're going live soon. When exactly?
-I can do it.
In four minutes.
She's sulking…
Why did you even bring her here?
-Which shoes?
-These.
Yes, we're ready.
Everyone, take your positions, please.
What are you staring at?
Please leave the set.
Take your positions!
Ready Camera Two, Camera Three!
The TV call-in contest!
Good evening!
This is our last call-in contest
of this millennium.
Easy… Slowly.
-You hear me?
-Uh-huh.
Good evening!
And now… stop!
We have the name
of the potential winner.
Now I need to focus for a second.
I must dial the right number…
Today, we're calling a distant town:
Sokołów Podlaski.
Try to be patient for a moment…
-Yes?
-Hello?
-Good evening, this is Mira Kryle.
Oh, hello, I'm Jadwiga Jeżewska.
-Are you watching us?
-Yes, of course.
-What am I doing?
-You're waving at me!
-I'm waving at you, too.
-He's got a gun!
-I'm so sorry I can't see that.
-I've won!
-Sorry, we're facing technical…
-Don't move.
-Don't show him! Switch to Mira!
-…technical difficulties…
-Don't move!
-Hello? Hello?
-Ladies and gentlemen, I'm here…
-We're off the air!
-To talk to you.
-Have I won the car?
What the fuck?! Is this a joke?
-You're crazy!
-Did they take us off? Freeze!
I can only see stripes.
They took us off the air, right?
-Hello…
-Turn them on.
Turn the cameras on!
Make them work! You hear me?
-Turn them on!
-It's the control room.
-Now I see the fireworks.
-They control it.
-People up there.
-Hello, can you hear me?
You, cuff yourself to her.
Ms. Mira, I can't hear you.
Ms. Mira, calm down.
More tightly!
And sit down.
Sit on your asses!
-We're going live, clear?!
-And who are you?
Hello?
Can we broadcast to the main channel?
We can fucking broadcast
to the whole of Poland.
Hello, can you hear me?
Marek! Are you recording this?
A separate tape for each camera.
I heard you a moment ago,
but I can't hear you now.
-Hello?
-Give her the award!
-You've won the main award!
-I've won it!
Happy New Year!
If you care about these two,
we'll go on air.
It's Nowacki, security.
Building E. E for Echo.
-They'll show you the way.
-Give me the cuffs.
We don't know how he got inside.
Maybe he's trained.
-Take them off! Now!
-Just a sec…
Let me go…
-He hasn't demanded any ransom.
-Hello?
He wants to talk.
Here's a microphone. You can…
It's not my duty.
No armed robberies.
My job is to check entry passes.
Hello?
Is there anyone up there?
Hello, can you hear me?
Laura! Hello?
Is there anyone up there?
I'm not sure.
Quiet! Quiet!
Hello?
Hello? You took your time!
-You must move towards the center.
-What?
You're standing too close to
the microphone. Interference.
-Who am I talking to?
-The producer.
I can't hear you!
Producer Laura Kołodziej.
Do you have any demands?
What is this about?
Let's end this funny little game.
Funny? You find this funny?
-Do you?! Is this funny?
-Not at all!
Can we talk normally?
Don't provoke him!
-Okay. Let's talk normally.
-He's coming here!
Get out, all of you! Sir, you stay!
Finally, a proper reaction.
Let's start again.
Let's start again! Slowly, okay?
First of all… Turn on the normal lights.
What are you doing?
That's good.
Get my live feed ready.
That's impossible. We have a schedule.
All right! I'll make a call.
Freeze!
Stop!
I'm sorry, I won't do it again.
No, no! Please!
Please, calm down.
-Mira!
-Sorry, I won't do it again.
-Sir! Please, don't hurt her!
-Fuck!
I'm sorry, I won't do it again.
-Sir! Please, don't hurt her!
-Get up!
Sir, I can't do this on my own.
I need… You have to tell me why..
I don't have to do anything!
Fine. How long is it going to be?
-A few minutes.
-What is it exactly?
I'm gonna spin the Wheel of Fortune!
Okay.
Okay, turn the stuff on and let's go.
I need time to get a crew together.
A camera operator,
men for sound and lighting.
Hurry up, then.
I'll make a few calls. Just stay calm.
I am calm.
Get into the car.
Get into the car!
Are you his accomplice?
What do you mean?
What do you guys want?
What's your point?
Ms. Mira, I've been working here
for two years.
Last winter, I helped you
with your broken car. Remember?
So, why aren't you doing anything?
You have to calm down
and do what he says.
Can I make an external call
from this phone?
Dial zero and the city code.
Move over to your seat.
Move.
Hello?
Dawid? Hi, it's me.
Fuck, you weren't supposed to call.
Yeah, I know.
Okay, what do you want?
Stop breathing into the phone and tell me.
I wanted to get in touch with you…
-In touch?
-Just to wish you a Happy New Year.
-You're nuts. I'm out, bye.
-No, hold on!
What?
Have you got a TV out there?
A TV?
You've got a TV out there, eh?
Yes, we've got a fucking TV.
-Watch it tonight.
-What?
Sebastian?
Sebastian!
Pessimists think that, on January 1st,
bank systems might collapse,
planes might go down,
and hospital devices
might stop working.
Plus, the millennium effect:
neurotic reactions, like preparing
for war-like conditions.
I've seen heaps of cans and tins,
packets of pasta.
Candles and matches,
supplies of water and coal.
People believe something
is going to happen at midnight.
Are you ready?
Yes.
I talk, you support.
You'll manage.
Who's the commanding officer?
Yes, sir.
Firefighters?
Guess they're already here.
Check that.
We need ambulances ready.
Shall we deploy?
On fucking New Year's Eve.
Laura, can you hear me?
Laura, please…
Get out.
Now!
I need to call my daughter's babysitter.
I should take her to Grandma's.
I'm a single mum.
-You won't call anyone.
-One call, please.
You won't call anyone, clear?
Who do you think you are?
Someone who doesn't like
emotional blackmail.
Where's the camera operator?
We're looking for someone brave enough
to enter the studio.
Let's offer people some entertainment!
The viewers are waiting!
-Hello?
-Hi, kid!
Congratulations! Are you having fun?
Is it going well?
Put me on the speaker.
I'd like to say something to Mira.
- Who's that?
- A crew member, your fan!
There's some fucking fun
in the studio, finally! Thanks, man.
Put me on the speaker.
Press the large button.
I'd like to talk to Mira.
Mira?
Mira, wave at the camera
if you can hear me.
Give me a sign…
Fuck me, you're so stupid.
I was wondering if you'd do it.
No smile?
You have a lovely smile for TV viewers.
No smile for work colleagues?
Do you recognize this voice?
No. But he's in the building
if he can see her.
Fuck off!
-Did you take a look?
-We assume it's live ammo.
The shooter is ready.
The bullet might ricochet off the glass.
Talk to him. We'll shoot the door.
Bang, bang, we get inside.
Someone might even survive.
No, no, calm down.
Stay ready and we'll negotiate.
-Can you start?
-Yes. Excuse me…
We're placing bets, you know?
Some say he's going to fucking kill you.
The others say
the guy doesn't have the balls…
It's the TV Chairman for you.
-How do you operate it?
-Krzysztof Jedynak, District Police.
Hello. No, he's not here. I'm here.
-Press this when you speak.
-Okay, thank you.
Are you threatening me?
We're doing our job.
-Ready?
-Yes.
Go ahead.
-Make a call, then.
-You must be having fun there.
You're listening to us
and it's oh, so funny.
A free cinema show.
Shall I wave?
A gang of frustrated pricks.
Who comes to work
on New Year's Eve, anyway?
What's your name?
Grzegorz.
Hello, Sebastian. My name is Piotr.
I'm here to help you handle your issue.
Where's the other lady?
Ms. Laura is here with me.
Together, we'll arrange
an operator for you.
I want to see you. Turn the light on
Sebastian, please lower your gun.
It's not necessary.
Please, don't aim your gun at me.
It makes me scared.
You should be. Turn the damn light on!
-Easy. Please, lower your gun.
-I'm coming over.
Turn the fucking light off, idiots!
Sebastian, don't do it!
-Lower your gun!
-Turn the light on!
Please lower your gun!
Don't move.
You're threatening
an innocent person with a gun.
Sebastian, please. Put the gun down.
And we can talk calmly.
-Turn the light on!
-Can we do it?
Stay in position! The light is on!
We've done what you asked for.
Can you show yourself?
-Is it on?
-Yes.
-Yes?!
What can you see?
What can you see?!
A lot of people.
-They're aiming their guns at me.
-Pigs, get the fuck out!
-Clear everyone out.
-Get out!
I can't see you. Please, show yourself.
Get out of there! Everyone!
They're still standing there.
There are ten or eleven of them.
-How many?
-Ten or eleven. With rifles.
Police officers, leave, please.
Leave so that nobody gets hurt.
Fine! We're pulling out.
Sebastian, we're fulfilling your wish.
The police are leaving.
Sebastian, I can't see you.
You, in the middle, stand up!
I knew it. Get the fuck out.
We'll go live,
and it's gonna end quickly.
The car.
The car, Grzesiek!
Move it here.
Put it in neutral.
Mira, move the camera away.
I can't see him. Where is he?
Get inside!
- Talk to him…
- Quiet!
I realize the sight of the police
aroused strong emotions.
I'm sorry you got upset.
-Give us a moment to handle your request.
-You have ten minutes!
Thank you.
Lend me your watch.
I'll give it back, don't worry.
We might have to let him go live.
What if he shoots Mira
or the guard while on air?
Or he shoots his head off?
Or he shouts, "Fuck the Jews"?
We'll cut in or go off the air.
That's out of the question!
We don't do such things on TV.
Even if we did,
it's not up to you or me to decide.
They're interrogating Dawid,
the guy he called.
We've learnt he has no criminal record.
He dropped out of Technical University.
He lives with his mother. An only child.
-Is that all?
-That's what that guy has told them.
-Two minutes.
-He almost looks like an operator.
I advise against it.
We'll have another hostage.
-Let's do our job.
-Tell them to instruct him.
What do you mean, he insists?
Get him down here. Just hurry up.
Thirty seconds!
Time's up!
-We've found an operator for you.
-Where is he?
On his way here.
We've granted your request.
Can you release one hostage?
You haven't done anything yet.
We're in a fucking TV station!
And there's no operator here?!
How long do I have to wait?!
It's not easy on New Year's Eve.
Everyone's busy with the concert.
I've had fucking enough
of your damn concert!
-Get out.
-Sebastian, you have a gun.
People are scared to enter the studio.
Get out. Get in front of the cameras.
I can't stand listening
about the operator.
We don't need anyone here.
I can help you with the cameras.
Ms. Mira, I can't hear you too well.
Can she operate it?
Is it true?
I don't know Ms. Mira's competencies.
I don't know his competencies.
I don't know this man.
I've been working here
for fifteen years.
I can…
…explain everything to you. Can I?
-They just have to broadcast it.
-Yes, please.
Grzesiek, take the chair
and sit on the set.
Ms. Mira, do you need anything?
When the camera is on,
there's a red light.
There are four cameras.
One, that's a wide shot. Two…
That's for close-ups.
Three is a medium shot.
-Stop her.
-How?
You can zoom… and focus.
You can't sit like him.
It doesn't look good.
Straighten up.
Sit properly.
When the lights and camera are on,
you may be speechless under pressure.
You must be prepared for that.
All right, get me through to broadcast.
We could have been inside by now!
You keep advising against everything.
What is your advice?
-Calm, first of all.
-Get me through to broadcast.
Answer him.
It's not that easy.
Sebastian, there's no one here
who can make such a decision.
Lower the gun, please.
Sebastian, lower the gun!
It's cocked. It can fire any time.
-Can you find someone now?
-Put the safety on.
Only the Chairman
can make such a decision.
Then get me the Chairman.
We're doing everything to get him here.
Lower your gun.
When will he be here?
It might take a while.
He's on his way here.
Fuck…
There is a way out.
Please, lower your gun.
We can do things differently.
It's not too late.
Article 252 of the Penal Code,
Point Four.
"Whoever releases the hostage
shall not be subject to the penalty."
So, am I supposed to lie down?
-And surrender?
-Lower your gun… Yes.
Okay, but it's Point Four, right?
What about the other three?
Please, lower your gun.
Point One, say it.
"Whoever takes a hostage
shall be imprisoned for three years."
-Point Two is irrelevant.
-Say it.
"If it is accompanied by torture,
from 3 to 25 years."
Remember Point Four, though.
"Whoever releases the hostage
shall not be subject to the penalty."
Here's the solution.
It's not too late, Sebastian.
Sebastian…
Let's keep talking.
We've achieved so much together.
Good, keep going.
"Whoever releases the hostage
shall not be subject to the penalty."
Sit down.
Pick one.
Take your pick!
I have a child.
How do you know he doesn't?
Do you?
I do.
What's your decision?
I hope we'll return home safely tonight.
Me, for sure. Take your pick.
-Sebastian, don't do it, please.
-Ten, nine…
-We were almost…
-Eight, seven…
Mira. Release Mira.
-Please, release Ms. Mira.
-Sit down.
You promised to release one person.
No, I didn't make any promises.
I just asked you to pick one.
I'm not talking to you. Keep quiet.
Until the Chairman arrives.
-Sebastian, I do apologize…
-Be quiet until the Chairman arrives!
What now?
-Eh?
-We're waiting.
-How long?
-Until he cools down.
-I don't have a magic password.
-How long?
-We might welcome in the New Year here.
-You must be joking.
-This boy is smart.
-Get the hell out of here!
He's playing with you.
-And Piotr thanks him.
-That's the procedure.
-He must think he's in charge.
-But he can't really be.
-Piotr can't control it.
-He had a tough operation.
-When?
-At the beginning of December.
-But he knows what to do.
-Was it the gas operation?
A murder-suicide? The guy blew up
his family and himself?
Fuck…
-The guy's by the entrance.
-Coming!
-How's it going?
-It's going. We need a moment.
This is a night
we've never experienced before,
and none of us ever will again.
I'm happy you stayed at home with us.
He should use simple words
when talking to miners.
-Coming up right now…
-Stay tuned for…
Please welcome Boney M!
Here, take a seat, please.
The monitors show the studio.
Like we've agreed,
you can talk about current issues.
I'll be here all the time.
We can stop it whenever you want.
OK.
Sebastian! Sebastian, can you hear me?
Someone would like to talk to you.
I'm not talking to you!
He's not from the TV station.
Look, he didn't know anything!
He didn't do anything!
Dawid, don't tell them anything!
You hear me?!
They have nothing on you!
Don't worry! You'll be just fine!
-Seb…
-You hear me?
Sebastian, it's me.
Can you hear me? It's me.
Show yourself, or I won't believe it.
Show yourself.
It's me.
That's just great.
You've put on weight.
You're doing well, eh?
Go home, you hear me? Go home.
You don't need this.
-I just want to help you.
-Whose idea was this?
God the Father has spoken
through loudspeakers.
Wrong address!
Dad, go home, please.
Go back to your place. Leave me here.
You don't have to do this.
We know everything. You've told me.
What exactly?
What exactly have I told you?
Where's Mum?
She didn't want to…
When they came to pick me up…
I thought something bad
had happened to you.
And what did you feel?
-What am I supposed to tell him?
-Tell me what you feel.
We can end this conversation
at any moment.
No, put him on. We'll h-h-have a chat.
Can we?
Let's just talk in a normal way.
In a normal way?
Have you looked around, man?
How is this "normal"?
How to put it…
I don't have time right now.
Listen, they're recording everything.
What do you need this for?
I don't know. As a keepsake?
What keepsake?
Please. Leave this place.
I can't.
You see, everyone's here because of me.
The TV Chairman is coming.
I'll have my own live TV show.
Your boy will be on TV.
Aren't you proud?
-Don't you want to sit…
-Stop it.
-…with your family in front of a…
-Stop showing off.
Stop acting like a clown.
-Please, calm down.
-For fuck's sake!
Go! Get out!
Step back!
Everyone, step back!
Try to stay calm, okay?
You're doing great.
-May I?
-Yes.
Sonny, I'm here.
Where did they pick you up?
We were at our neighbors'.
The New Year's Eve party…
Listen to me.
Let these people out. After all…
I talked to the police officers…
You'll go to hospital, and…
You want to lock me up
in a hospital, don't you?
How's your new wife doing?
I'm sure she's pissed off, eh?
What's this all about? Me?
Surprisingly enough,
it's not about you this time.
So what's your point, then?
Do you know how your mother feels?
-Keep Mum out of this.
-They came to her place first.
Your mother said
she didn't want to watch her…
…her only son…
Say it.
Or shall I s-s-say it?
Don't you have any shame at all?
-I have nothing to be ashamed of.
-Really?
Did he stutter before, too?
-Are you going to stutter on air, then?
-We must end this!
Are you? Did you think about that?
What will happen if you stutter on air?
Don't run away now!
Sebastian!
Have you already forgotten?
Coming here? To a clinic in Warsaw?
He didn't speak for six months.
Then the training started,
and there was a breakthrough.
He started to speak in syllables.
You forgot?
"What did you have for lunch, son?"
"I… haaad…"
"…meatbaaalls…"
"…fooor luuunch…"
And we couldn't interrupt him.
We had to listen patiently.
"What else did you have?
What else, son?"
"I… haaad… sooome… saaa… laaad…"
"…aaand… fruuuit… juuuice…"
Shut the fuck up!
Sit down.
He bottled it up for a long time.
Now you c-c-can sleep at night, eh?
You remember that?
"The… worst…"
Fuck.
"…is…"
"…is first."
Let me fucking finish, just this once!
"The worst…"
"The worst… is first."
You remember that?
You do.
You're going to like it in prison.
You'll see.
You hear me?
In prison, they'll get…
In prison, they'll get
your sick lifestyle out of you
when they fuck you in the ass!
They'll get it out of you in prison!
This way, please. Follow me.
-How could you let this happen?
-This meaning what?
Change your tone when talking to me.
The brat saw his daddy and broke down.
-He won't control us.
-You must listen to my advice.
It's your first operation.
You wanted to come here yourself, right?
-Control your emotions!
-We both file reports.
-Report what you wish.
-He's not talking to you.
Neither am I.
The police came
and started asking questions.
I had to see it with my own eyes.
I thought that maybe…
My father was very strict with me.
Sebastian had everything. Everything.
He dropped out of university
because he was too lazy.
You think I'm proud of the way
it turned out?
Of the fact that I failed the first time?
I always paid child maintenance on time.
What can a twenty-year-old know
about kids or life?
Nothing.
"The worst is first."
That's what I blurted out once.
He pissed me off.
You can see how provocative he is.
Every conversation with him is just…
Do you think your son is capable
of hurting anyone?
Now, I'm a little ashamed…
What did you ask me?
Do you think your son is capable
of hurting anyone?
How can I tell?
I don't know him.
Give us our pay, end poverty today!
We are people of the last decade.
We've entered a new century…
It's easy to say, "We'll give you money."
But it's hard to say,
"We will not give you money."
Get up!
I want you to swap!
Rookie, sit down. You, move your ass.
Don't argue with me!
-What's going on?
-You'll do the talking.
-Start talking.
-Wait!
We can't wait! Say something.
Sebastian?
I want to apologize to you
for the situation with your father.
It was a mistake. I admit that.
Your father wanted to come here himself.
We know neither you nor him.
-We shouldn't have done it.
-Where is he?
I agreed to it, too,
so I apologize, okay?
My name is Lena.
Find out where the hostages are.
I want to see them.
Can you tell me
how Ms. Mira and Mr. Grzegorz are?
Ms. Mira?
Mr. Grzegorz?
We haven't seen you for a long time.
I understand you don't want to talk.
But we're simply worried about you.
May we perhaps see you?
How do you turn it?
What's going on?
-There… Both of them.
-Where is that?
-Down here?
-Okay?
Thank you.
But it would be easier to talk to you
if I could see your face.
You got a good look at me!
Isn't that enough? You've even met my dad.
Now I'll be watching you.
Quite a crowd up there.
Show me your face. Where are you?
Come up closer.
Here's a mic.
You've been watching a show,
now it's our turn.
-Can you see him?
-No.
So, how does it make you feel?
Do you like yourself?
What do you like about yourself?
I'm not sure. My eyes?
What don't you like?
Everything that's below.
-You don't want to be on TV?
-Get ready.
You don't like it?
Everyone wants to be on TV.
No, not me.
And you?
You're here about TV, right?
Do you actually watch TV?
Sometimes.
If you watched it more often,
you'd know.
Know what?
You know how much time
the Poles spend in front of the TV?
Four hours. Four hours a day.
You know how much you can do
in four hours?
Quite a lot of things.
A lot.
-What would you do?
-I don't know. Normal things.
I'd fix lunch for myself.
I'd walk the dog.
What if these were your final four hours?
Keep talking.
I'd go to a solarium.
Why are you laughing?
You've surprised me, that's all.
To a solarium…
Interesting priorities.
People have been placing bets
concerning you.
What did they bet on?
Different things.
Most often, you're unemployed.
Or you're a student
who was expelled from university.
Maybe you're a farmer's son,
or you're ill
and your medical financing was cut.
What did you bet on?
It's something personal,
or you wouldn't have called Dawid.
You wanted him to watch, right?
I assure you, he won't get into trouble.
Get ready. The hostages are on the left.
Beta team ready.
I feel this is really important.
-Wait.
-Fuck…
Pretty important, eh?
You guys are obsessed with importance.
It is important to me and you!
-To others, not really.
-I get it.
No, you don't. You don't.
The viewers will believe
anything I say to the camera.
Move in! Go, go!
-What's going on?
-Sebastian…
There's a sound failure.
Are you fucking nuts?! Turn it off!
You think I'm an idiot?
-Turn it up!
-Turn it off!
-Calm down, lower your gun.
-What if I have a bomb?!
Repeat, please. I can't hear you!
Such a crowd, and none of you asked!
He's got a bomb.
-There's a bomb. Evacuation!
-What now?
-Evacuation!
-It complicates a lot of things.
-What's going on?
-I have to leave.
Don't go!
It's the procedure. I'll be back!
Lena!
Talk to me, Lena!
Do something!
Attention! This is the police.
Please stay calm
and proceed to emergency exits.
The police will show you
the evacuation route.
Hello! Hey! Hello?
Hello!
Please stay calm
and proceed to emergency exits.
This is an emergency evacuation!
Who's gonna get you on air now?!
There's nobody…
What the fuck are you staring at?
The whole fucking building
has been evacuated.
What now?!
Grzesiek? Grzesiek!
Grzesiek!
This is an evacuation route. Leave now.
Are you sure we can contact him from here?
-Yes.
-Fine.
Secure the area! Walk them out!
Grzesiek! Hey! Grzesiek!
Is there any water here?
I asked you a question!
Fuck…
Grzesiek! Wake up!
Grzesiek, hey!
Come on!
Are the AV cables ready yet?
All right.
-The intercom is vital for us.
-I'll connect it right away.
Hazard lights have slowed down.
Can I?
Sure, have some at last.
Could you stop…
…aiming your gun at us?
I graduated from a theatre school.
I can play anything.
How did you end up here?
Classic.
They had a blonde, a brunette,
and a ginger girl,
so they needed someone in between.
With charisma.
Please, calm down.
I won't answer any questions
if you all talk at once.
-Please, comment on that!
-You're lying!
Next week,
I'm starting my military service.
But I see no future for me here.
I'm at school, but then,
I kind of don't know.
Next year, I'll finish school
and go abroad.
I'm still at school,
then I'll go to university.
And I'll go abroad, too.
Yeah, me too.
The awards go to Grzegorz!
I was almost late for work.
Tonight.
But I came on fucking time.
Laura had already found…
Kasia?
-The weather girl?
-Kasia Jaworska.
They even gave her my fucking dress!
You'd be sitting here with Kasia.
-Just follow me.
-Kasia, the lapel mic!
We'll interview them in the corridor.
I don't really know…
I was having dinner,
then I was reading…
I didn't hear anything.
I found out afterwards.
About the gun and so on.
Everything was ready
for the millennium party.
The Christmas tree, tables,
but suddenly…
He was aggressive, and sometimes…
He walked like an animal in a cage,
which we saw on studio cameras.
He seemed unstable.
Such a young man.
What did he want to say?
It looks like an act of desperation.
It must be something important
if he's so determined.
-Sebastian? Can you hear me?
-Please, try again.
Sebastian?
Andrzej Kostecki. I'm the TV Chairman.
Is this your idea? Great.
-Ms. Mira…
-Who's the commanding officer?
-Who did I talk to?
-Me.
-Mr. Grzegorz, can you hear me?
-Sebastian?
-No connection.
-What's going on out there?
-Quiet, please.
It's the Chairman.
Sebastian, can you hear me? They can't.
Sebastian?
We can hear you.
So, you've got the signal?
Yes. I can see and hear you.
I'm sorry it took so long.
Do you need anything?
Water, food, medicine?
No! You can put the Chairman on the phone.
He was so outspoken a minute ago,
let him speak now.
-I can talk to him.
-Come on, Kostecki!
Guess we have no choice.
Please, sit down.
Is he wasted?
And you're afraid to put him on?
-Can I?
-Yes.
Hello?
Hello, this is Andrzej Kostecki.
Because of the bomb,
we had to evacuate the building.
We're in a different building.
But we can broadcast, eh?
We've been waiting just for you!
We must handle some technical aspects.
Hurry up, because I'm going on air
after the President.
Do you know when he's done?
We don't know how long
his New Year's speech will be.
-Find out, then!
-We do.
It's taped.
Andrzej, right?
-Yes.
-Look, Andrzej. Don't fuck with me.
You don't have a choice.
Either broadcast, or them.
-I can't make this decision alone.
-Well, you fucking can!
-I'll make a few calls…
-What's your job, then?
-Easy…
-Why the fuck did we wait for you?
What game are you guys playing?
-Good evening, sir!
-Hello, Ms. Mira!
I'd really like to stay calm,
but I'm just a bag of nerves.
Yes, Ms. Mira. Please, trust me.
-Everything's going to be fine.
-I'll try.
I understand it all, you know.
I just want to know what's going on.
Please, calm down.
This is a police procedure.
It's fucking shit, then.
The procedure's fucking shit.
You've left us completely alone here.
You know how it feels?
Did anyone ask about "our Mira",
or did they just
get the fuck out of there?
Did anyone think about me?
-You know how it feels…
-Ms. Mira…
…to be left completely alone?
Calm down.
We're all thinking about you.
We're taking care of you.
Stay calm and don't be hysterical.
All right.
All right…
Oh, just fuck this!
Where's she going?
Hi, Monika. This is Mira Kryle.
We can talk on New Year's Eve, at least.
-Where are you partying tonight?
-This is a business call.
-Turn it off now!
-But it's not me…
-Turn it off! Now!
-…an armed man in my studio…
-For fuck's sake…
-You're drunk.
No, I'm not drunk.
He's standing right there.
-Who is she calling?
-Our competition.
Call anyone you want.
Everyone's here, listening to us.
The Chairman is here.
You're the first person I've called.
You want this?
She called her
because she was hysterical.
I won't leave this place.
Say it's going okay.
Going okay?
You have to arrest that woman.
-For what?
-The lack of a fire extinguisher.
Andrzej Kostecki, yes?
Oh, yes, sir, I've just talked to him.
Can't you stop it
through the National TV Council?
Hold on.
You can have a live interview.
What do you say?
Yes or no?
-Give me a few minutes, okay?
-Sure.
-Can I call you back?
-Dial the main number and 501.
-Okay.
-Thanks, Monika. I'm waiting.
Fuck… I hope it's worth it.
If I were you, I'd have already shot us.
Sebastian, you've got it. You can go live.
Audio and video, everything. You hear me?
We're preparing the live feed.
Please, just bear with us.
Ms. Laura will talk to you
about the technical details.
This is our fifth meeting
on New Year's Eve.
Yet, the moment of this meeting
is exceptional:
the threshold of the year 2000.
It happens once
every two thousand years.
Grzegorz, can you do something
to show me his face?
Now, I can see the gun.
Pull up, please. Don't cut the head off.
Mr. Sebastian,
can you take your cap off, please?
I can't see your eyes.
Thank you.
Can you move the TV?
I'd like to see myself.
I'll powder your face.
You're too sweaty.
-How long?
-Two minutes.
You go on air
after the President and the info board.
How long should the intro be?
-Two or three sentences.
-I have to comb you.
Something neutral like,
"Here's a special announcement"?
Keep it short. One minute forty.
Will you let him go live?
Your task is to provide him
with audio and video.
This is Laura Kołodziej.
Synchronize the studio, please.
Can we check my mic?
-One, two, three…
-Pin it higher.
Higher? One, two, three…
One, one, one…
-One, one, one…
-Fine.
One minute to air.
Smooth your hair at the back.
At the back?
Cameras Two and Three only,
because my shoes aren't done.
Don't worry. The main one is Camera Two.
45 seconds to air.
All right. I'll introduce you.
Then I'll leave the platform,
and you stand right here.
-You can read, if you want.
-Please, don't talk to me now.
Those of you who are spending
this night not exactly as you wish,
please accept my warmest greetings
of luck and happiness.
I also remember those
who work hard to create our reality.
Workers, entrepreneurs,
scholars and scientists, teachers,
artists, doctors and nurses, priests,
local activists and community workers.
There are more and more of us.
We need to live wisely to prosper.
In harmony with the world,
in peace and friendship.
The world doesn't belong
to the rulers or people with power,
or those who skillfully
increase their fortunes,
or the best-educated people.
-Please, turn it off.
-The world belongs to everyone.
Let's look forward
to meeting the 21st century.
This is a challenge and a chance.
You go on air in fifteen seconds.
Nine, eight, seven, six…
-Are you ready?
-…five, four, three, two…
This is a special edition of our show.
I'm Mira Kryle, good evening.
There are such moments
even TV people aren't ready for.
We're interrupting our schedule…
Nothing.
-We're on air…
-We're fucking not.
-Sebastian, don't.
-You thought I wouldn't check?
Sebastian, please!
Now!
Lights!
Turn on the lights!
Grzesiek! Mira! On the ground!
Mira, get on the ground.
Mira!
-Sebastian, what's going on?
-Fuck me.
-Hold the assault. Lights on.
-Did you know about it?
-Do something!
-What the fuck is this?
-Get them out of here!
-Quiet!
Sebastian, tell us what's happened, okay?
-Grzegorz, get the first aid kit.
-Can you hear me? Tell me.
We have a doctor here.
Can you hear me?
Fuck… It's empty!
-Ms. Mira?
-She needs to go to hospital.
If something's wrong… just tell me.
-Sebastian, if you need a doctor…
-You hear them?
-It's your fault…
-Sebastian!
It's your fault!
Calm down, please.
Please tell us what's happened.
-It's your fault!
-I don't know what to say.
-What are you doing?
-Going in there.
-What will you tell him?
-No idea. I'll go down for this anyway.
Who's in command now?!
Mira, calm down. You're insured, right?
You'll get money for this.
Get off me!
-I'm alone and unarmed!
-Hands up!
I've got water.
Can I see Ms. Mira?
I'll open it a bit. Slowly.
Oh, fuck.
I'll squat.
Everything's gonna be fine.
Listen… This has all gone too far.
Let her go.
I'll take her.
And you won't have to worry about her.
You still have company.
Take her.
-No!
-Once more.
-No, no!
-Shit… Calm down.
I have to go inside.
Stop. Freeze!
I have no weapon. Easy.
Lower your gun.
I'll take this chair, okay?
-Take it and get the fuck out of here.
-Help me, okay?
Help him!
-No, no!
-Easy…
Watch out for the threshold!
What are you doing? Come here!
Sebastian?
How is she?
She was taken to hospital.
Here's an act of goodwill.
No, it wasn't supposed to happen.
I don't, and I didn't,
want you to get hurt.
You don't have to go to prison,
you know that?
It's too late for that.
Something's happened.
No, listen to me. There is a way.
You know the Penal Code.
You may not be fully aware.
If they decide you're insane,
you'll go to…
-Stop, Lena. Enough.
-Fuck!
Can't you see that?
-You've crossed the line.
-What?!
Grzesiek, go home.
To your wife and kids.
-I'm sorry.
-For what, man?
I have no wife or kids.
Go, now!
-Please.
-Thank you.
Sebastian, this is Andrzej Kostecki,
the TV Chairman.
You knew it wouldn't be easy
for an amateur to go live.
See, I thought I'd make it.
It doesn't have to end like this.
You know that.
You're smart. You can't waste this chance.
This might be your only chance.
We can tape it.
A lot of technicians are still at work.
There are crowds outside the building,
reporters, waiting for your story.
Your huge story.
Perfect for the prime time.
Sure, it depends on what you're…
Sebastian!
Don't just think about yourself.
Think about all those young people
who will be inspired by you.
We can squeeze out some value
for your generation.
-Which camera? This one?
-Yes, this one.
Is the tape recorder on?
Yes, it is.
Maybe you can rehearse something?
No, there's no need to.
Say what you feel to the camera.
Only that. Start when you're ready.
I am.
-No!
-Sebastian, lower your gun.
It's not necessary.
Please, don't do this.
The second hostage is safe.
-Are we going in or waiting?
-Launch the assault.
-Everyone ready to attack!
-Get on the ground!
Get on the ground!
Don't resist!
Police! Step away from the door!
-Lie down on the ground!
-Three, two, one!
Police!
Look at me! Show me your hands!
Look at me!
Cover the cameras!
Do something, please.
Get out of my way!
You're coming with me.
Come on!
Show me your tongue! Cough!
We're filming this!
-Get out! Leave this place now!
-Don't touch me!
Don't touch the camera!
Wake up! Move it, you piece of shit!
I'd like to knock on your doors.
Keep your head down!
Can we clean this place up now?
Subtitle translation by: Magdalena C